{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Whoopi Goldberg","incorrectAnswers":["Frances McDormand","Katharine Hepburn","Gloria Swanson"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Oda Mae Brown in Ghost?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cock","incorrectAnswers":["A Rooster","A Cob","A Ram"],"question":"A male bird is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bob Geldof","incorrectAnswers":["Bono","Freddie Mercury","Sting"],"question":"Who was the founder of Live Aid?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the studio album 'Unapologetic'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"What I Got\" by Sublime","incorrectAnswers":["\"Rapper's Delight\" by Sugarhill Gang","\"Fergalicious\" by Fergie and will.i.am.","\"In da Club\" by 50 Cent"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Early in the morning, risin' to the street / Light me up that cigarette, and I'll strap shoes on my feet...\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Korean War","incorrectAnswers":["World War II","The American War of Independence","The Vietnam War"],"question":"Which war began on June 25, 1950?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Peter Sellers","incorrectAnswers":["James Cagney","Michael Douglas","Johnny Depp"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Chance the Gardener in Being There?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Egypt","incorrectAnswers":["Tunisia","Morocco","Algeria"],"question":"Which country celebrates Suez National Day?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pre-Raphaelite","incorrectAnswers":["Neo-Raphaelite","Pre-Jacobian","Neo-Jacobian"],"question":"A group of English painters formed in 1848. These artists attempted to recapture an old style of painting. They rejected industrialized England and focused on painting from nature, producing detailed, colorful works. What were they called?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Claude Monet","incorrectAnswers":["Michelangelo","René Magritte","Vincent van Gogh"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Water Lilies\"","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"2001, A Space Odyssey","incorrectAnswers":["Star Wars","Alien","E.T."],"question":"In what film does the HAL 9000 appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hebrew","incorrectAnswers":["Arabic","English","Greek"],"question":"What is the official language of Israel?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The meter","incorrectAnswers":["The rhyme","The consonance","The alliteration"],"question":"What word refers to the rhythmic structure of a poem?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Milk ","incorrectAnswers":["Honey","Wheat","Citrus Fruits"],"question":"Where might you find lactose?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"H. G. Wells","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","Arthur C. Clarke","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Time Machine'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Chile","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","France","Argentina"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1962 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Maldives is on which continent?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Joseph Stalin","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Lenin","Nikita Khrushchev","Peter the Great"],"question":"Who was the ruler of the Soviet Union from 1924 to his death, leading the Soviet Union in WWII?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Toronto ","incorrectAnswers":["Bordeaux","Seattle","Budapest"],"question":"What's the most southerly of these cities?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Elephant","incorrectAnswers":["Gorilla","Tiger","Brown Bear"],"question":"Excluding humans, what is the longest living land mammal?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Zeus","incorrectAnswers":["Hephaestus","Agamemnon","Achilles"],"question":"Who was Hercules' father?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Oakland A's","incorrectAnswers":["Oakland Yankees","Oakland Tigers","Oakland Mavericks"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Oakland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Holiday Inn","incorrectAnswers":["Miracle on 34th Street","White Christmas","The Holly & The Ivy"],"question":"What Was The Name Of The Film Which First Featured Bing Crosby's Song 'White Christmas''?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Sousaphone","incorrectAnswers":["Cymbal","Piccolo","Sitar"],"question":"Which of these is a brass instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Meldrop","incorrectAnswers":["Agastopia","Blatherskite","Tittynope"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'A drop of mucus at the nose, whether produced by cold or otherwise'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Wood","incorrectAnswers":["Sand","Earth","Clay"],"question":"From What material do wasps build their nests?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"John F. Kennedy","incorrectAnswers":["Theodore Roosevelt","Abraham Lincoln","Barack Obama"],"question":"Who was the youngest person ever elected president of the USA?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South Korea","incorrectAnswers":["China","Cameroon","Germany"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Percy Jackson & the Olympians","The Hunger Games","His Dark Materials"],"question":"In which book series does 'Hagrid' appear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Stratford-Upon-Avon","incorrectAnswers":["Bath","York","Norwich"],"question":"Where in England was William Shakespeare born?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Vijf","incorrectAnswers":["Cinque","Fünf","Groen"],"question":"What is the Dutch word for 'five'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Avon","incorrectAnswers":["The Thames","The Severn","The Mersey"],"question":"Which river in England has both a Welford-on- and a Bidford-on- location?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Water ","incorrectAnswers":["Beer","Tea","Apple Juice"],"question":"Which drink is sometimes referred to as Adam's ale?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mother of Pearl","incorrectAnswers":["Faux Satin","Fool's Gold","Diamond"],"question":"What is the lustrous material which lines the inside of an abalone shell?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Fudgel","incorrectAnswers":["Bumfuzzle","Groke","Whippersnapper"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'Pretending to work when you’re not actually doing anything at all'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Sino-Tibetan","Japonic","Niger–Congo"],"question":"The language 'Bavarian' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Joey","incorrectAnswers":["A Cygnet","A Farrow","A Caterpillar"],"question":"What would you call a baby wombat?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Daniel Kaluuya","incorrectAnswers":["Sacha Baron Cohen","Leslie Odom, Jr.","Paul Raci"],"question":"Who won the 2020 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Fred Hampton in Judas and the Black Messiah?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Herman Melville","incorrectAnswers":["Robert A. Heinlein","James Fenimore Cooper","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Moby-Dick'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vilnius","incorrectAnswers":["The Hague","Düsseldorf","Frankfurt"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Lithuania?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Rupee ","incorrectAnswers":["The Rand","The Lekh","The Dinar"],"question":"What Is The Unit Of Currency In India?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Elephant Man","incorrectAnswers":["Vertigo","Back to the Future","Mr. Smith Goes to Washington"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A surgeon rescues a disfigured man who is mistreated while scraping a living as a side-show freak.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1998","incorrectAnswers":["1989","1992","1995"],"question":"In which year was Saving Private Ryan released?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Johnny Depp","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Downey Jr.","Keanu Reeves","Brad Pitt"],"question":"Which actor has played roles such as Willy Wonka and Gilbert Grape?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Henri Matisse","incorrectAnswers":["Leonardo da Vinci","Gustav Klimt","Claude Monet"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Dance\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nokia","incorrectAnswers":["Google","Vodafone","Verizon"],"question":"'Connecting people' is a slogan associated with which technology brand?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Silence of the Lambs","incorrectAnswers":["Casablanca","A Nightmare on Elm Street","Taxi Driver"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Hannibal Lecter'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Cambodia","Vietnam","Laos"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Malaysia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Boer War","incorrectAnswers":["The Zulu War","The Anglo-Saxon War","The African Colonization War"],"question":"Which war did the UK fight in South Africa between 1899 and 1902?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mauritius","incorrectAnswers":["New Zealand","Fiji","The Philippines"],"question":"Which island country lies to the West of Australia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Tempest'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A raconteur","incorrectAnswers":["A troubadour","A dilettante","A bard"],"question":"What term for someone who tells stories and anecdotes with skill and wit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Great Plague","incorrectAnswers":["The Napoleonic Wars","The Fall of Rome","The Discovery of the New World"],"question":"What historic event does the nursery rhyme 'Ring-a-ring of roses' commemorate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["Cambodia","Croatia","China"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Uluru?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Frankenstein","incorrectAnswers":["Great Expectation","Ullyses","Of Mice and Men"],"question":"Which novel opens and closes with the letters of Robert Walton?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Psycho","incorrectAnswers":["Vertigo","Rebecca","North by Northwest"],"question":"In which Alfred Hitchcock thriller was there a famous shower scene?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Muhammad Ali and Joe Frazier","incorrectAnswers":["Mike Tyson and Lennox Lewis","Floyd Mayweather and Manny Pacquiao","George Foreman and Evander Holyfield"],"question":"Which 2 boxers fought in 1971's 'Fight of the Century'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gérard Depardieu","incorrectAnswers":["Jean Reno","Alain Delon","Vincent Cassel"],"question":"Which French actor has featured in films including Cyrano de Bergerac and La Vie en Rose?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Saint George's","incorrectAnswers":["London","Asunción","Sarajevo"],"question":"What is the capital city of Grenada?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Manama","incorrectAnswers":["Dubai","Beirut","Bursa"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Bahrain?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Schnapps ","incorrectAnswers":["Brandy","Vodka","Rum"],"question":"Which German spirit is flavoured with caraway seeds and distilled from potatoes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Poland","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","Slovenia","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Germany?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Choux ","incorrectAnswers":["Filo","Puff","Flaky"],"question":"What pastry is used to make profittaroles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Siam","incorrectAnswers":["Khmer","Kambucha","Burma"],"question":"What was the former name of Thailand?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Simon & Garfunkel","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American music duo released the studio album 'Bridge over Troubled Water'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Rabbit","incorrectAnswers":["Squirrel","Pig","Anteater"],"question":"What animal lives in a warren?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"New Mexico","incorrectAnswers":["Nagasaki","Hiroshima","Bikini Atoll"],"question":"Where did the first atomic bomb explode?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Carol","incorrectAnswers":["Blessing","Chant","Anthem"],"question":"What is the general term for a Christmas song or hymn?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eva Cassidy","incorrectAnswers":["Norah Jones","Dido","Karen Carpenter"],"question":"Whose Album 'Songbird' Became A Posthumous Hit In 2001?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Spain","Greece","Turkey"],"question":"Which country fits snugly between the Tyrrhenian and Adriatic Seas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hajj","incorrectAnswers":["Ramadan","Halal","Mecca"],"question":"Which of the following is one of the five pillars of Islam?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Angela Lansbury","incorrectAnswers":["Anne Bancroft","Katharine Hepburn","Holly Hunter"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Mrs. Iselin in The Manchurian Candidate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iraq","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Russia","Turkey"],"question":"Where are the great Walls of Babylon located in the modern day world ?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Eclipse","incorrectAnswers":["Waning","Transmutation","Occultation"],"question":"What is the word for when the light from a star is blocked by another celestial object?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Great","incorrectAnswers":["Large","Grand","Happy"],"question":"What word precedes both 'Dane' and 'Depression'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Brandy","incorrectAnswers":["Gin","Wine","Whiskey"],"question":"Made in France, what type of alcohol is Armagnac?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"There's no crying in baseball!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Forget it, Jake, it's Chinatown.\"","\"We rob banks.\"","\"Striker: Surely you can't be serious.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'A League of Their Own'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia","Latvia","Lithuania"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Finland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'canon of Sherlock Holmes'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A yo-yo","incorrectAnswers":["A frisbee","A hula hoop","A skipping rope"],"question":"Which toy includes tricks like 'walking the dog' and 'around the world'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Monaco","Switzerland","Luxembourg"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Andorra?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Strudel","incorrectAnswers":["Tart","Croissant","Custard Pie"],"question":"Which of these is a layered pastry traditionally made with a rich, sweet filling?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A girl wanders into a world ruled by gods, witches, and spirits, where humans are changed into beasts.","incorrectAnswers":["An insane American general orders a bombing attack on the Soviet Union.","Held captive for 7 years, a woman and her young son finally gain their freedom.","A withdrawn boy who communicates with spirits seeks the help of a child psychologist."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Spirited Away?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hong Kong","incorrectAnswers":["Taiwan","Shanghai","Beijing"],"question":"Which Chinese special administrative region is located on the other side of the Pearl River estuary from Macau?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ural","incorrectAnswers":["Pyrenees","Alps","Carpathian"],"question":"What mountain range separates Europe from Asia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Green Day","incorrectAnswers":["Mastodon","Animal Collective","Fall Out Boy"],"question":"Which band includes 'Billie Joe Armstrong'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Brazil","Spain"],"question":"Which country won the 2006 FIFA World Cup, hosted in Germany?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jin Yong","incorrectAnswers":["C. S. Lewis","Edgar Rice Burroughs","J. K. Rowling"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Legend of the Condor Heroes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1950","incorrectAnswers":["1934","1942","1958"],"question":"In which year did the Korean War begin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Philip Pullman","incorrectAnswers":["J. R. R. Tolkien","Christopher Tolkien","Neil Gaiman"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Subtle Knife'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Belgium","Argentina","Israel"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Mont Saint Michel?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Endangered species","incorrectAnswers":["Exotic species","Invasive species","Declining species"],"question":"What is the term for animals that are at risk of becoming extinct?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Persia ","incorrectAnswers":["Parthia","Mesopotamia","Assyria"],"question":"Prior to 1935 what was Iran known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Swimwear","incorrectAnswers":["Suits","Hats","Dresses"],"question":"What type of clothing is Anne Cole is known for designing?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Benedict Cumberbatch","incorrectAnswers":["Jeff Goldblum","J.K. Simmons","Michael Douglas"],"question":"Which actor plays the role of Dr Strange in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"That's All Right, Mama","incorrectAnswers":["Blue Suede Shoes","Teddy Bear","Hound Dog"],"question":"What was the first Elvis Presley single released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A young girl and her dog are swept away by a tornado from their Kansas farm to a magical land.","incorrectAnswers":["A man with short-term memory loss attempts to track down his wife's murderer.","The jury in a murder trial is frustrated by a member whose caution forces them to consider the evidence.","A former neo-nazi tries to prevent his brother from going down the same path that he did."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Wizard of Oz?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Belgium","incorrectAnswers":["France","The USA","Australia"],"question":"French fries come from which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Paul Simon","incorrectAnswers":["Elton John","Usher","Prince"],"question":"Who Wrote the song \"Fifty Ways To Leave Your Lover\"?","difficulty":"hard"},